<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Yawar's website</title><link>https://yawar5.github.io/website/</link><description>Recent content on Yawar's website</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 12 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://yawar5.github.io/website/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Travelling, Growing, Remembering What Matters</title><link>https://yawar5.github.io/website/posts/eleventh-post/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://yawar5.github.io/website/posts/eleventh-post/</guid><description>I’ve been moving quite a bit these past few years — from the streets of Marseille and the dunes of Morocco, to family visits in the UK, bike rides through Italy, long walks in in Dublin and long talks in Orlando, busy evenings in Pakistan and long drives in Brazil, and spiritual moments in Saudi Arabia. Each place left a trace. Not just on my passport, but in how I think, feel, and want to live my life.</description></item><item><title>🕊️ Bridging Borders: Reflections on recent Pakistan - India conflict</title><link>https://yawar5.github.io/website/posts/tenth-post/</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://yawar5.github.io/website/posts/tenth-post/</guid><description>🏡 Introduction: Home Beyond Borders #As I stood on my balcony in the Netherlands on a quiet Saturday evening, the sun warmed my skin while my thoughts drifted to Pakistan.
Born and raised there for 20 years before studying in Italy and building a life in the Netherlands, I’ve come to understand that “home” is not one place—it’s layered. And while I may now live across continents, Pakistan will always live in me.</description></item><item><title>Three takeaways from 2024</title><link>https://yawar5.github.io/website/posts/ninth-post/</link><pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://yawar5.github.io/website/posts/ninth-post/</guid><description>While an entire year has passed by since I posted three takeaways from 2023 covering the aspects of travelling, taking risk, having a positive attitude towards life, I find myself asking once again what the learning from this year (2024) are. So, with this post I would like to document them in following three takeaways (3Fs) from 2024.
1st takeaway: Family #With limited time on this planet, one’s family rightly should be among the central pillars when it comes to prioritising and dedicating one’s time in a prudent manner.</description></item><item><title>Lessons learned from industry so far</title><link>https://yawar5.github.io/website/posts/eigth-post/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://yawar5.github.io/website/posts/eigth-post/</guid><description>It has been two years since my full-time transition from academia to industry. I was involved in industry long before this full transition, during four years of industrial PhD from 2018 to 2022 to be exact, but in the past two years of full-time work in industry, I have learned a lot of new lessons that I want to summarize here in the following three lessons learned.
Lesson #1: Mindset matters alot.</description></item><item><title>Three takeaways from 2023</title><link>https://yawar5.github.io/website/posts/seventh-post/</link><pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://yawar5.github.io/website/posts/seventh-post/</guid><description>The last sun of 2023 will set in a few hours, and I would like to take this moment to reflect and capture some of the most important takeaways of the past year for me. If I had to describe this year in one word, for me it would be ‘Lively’. During the year it didn&amp;rsquo;t seem that impactful, but looking back now, it feels like a lot happened in just one year.</description></item><item><title>How to get to know your gut feeling?</title><link>https://yawar5.github.io/website/posts/sixth-post/</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://yawar5.github.io/website/posts/sixth-post/</guid><description>There is a good chance that we have all heard of gut feeling. As a PhD holder in knowledge management, &amp;ldquo;gut feeling&amp;rdquo; was one of the most popular words I used when I had to explain the concept of tacit knowledge. Tacit knowledge refers to the kind of knowledge that is either difficult or, in some cases, impossible to put into words. So I take the challenge and try to put the idea of gut feeling into words by explaining how you can know your gut feeling.</description></item><item><title>Flood relief operation in Pakistan</title><link>https://yawar5.github.io/website/posts/fifth-post/</link><pubDate>Sun, 23 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://yawar5.github.io/website/posts/fifth-post/</guid><description>I am pleased to share that we have successfully completed the relief operation for the flood victims in Pakistan. Thanks to the support of all donors, 570 euros were raised for the flood relief operation through the gofundme campaign. The money raised was sent to an acquaintance who led the relief operation. The relief operation carried out consisted of the following activities:
Distribution of 40 food bags, 10 mosquito nets, and pre-cooked food boxes on 6 October.</description></item><item><title>PhD</title><link>https://yawar5.github.io/website/projects/first-project/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://yawar5.github.io/website/projects/first-project/</guid><description>I am grateful and humbled to have completed my PhD on the topic Advancing knowledge management for system integration: Improving the management of lessons learned to enhance organisational learning and railway system performance last Friday, 14 October 2022.
The video below provides a detailed insight into the topics discussed during my PhD defence and subsequent cermony!
Feel free to check out my PhD thesis if you want to know more about my research.</description></item><item><title>What is success in life?</title><link>https://yawar5.github.io/website/posts/fourth-post/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://yawar5.github.io/website/posts/fourth-post/</guid><description>It was my pleasure to have a conversation with Wilbert Wijns about the meaning of success in life. Wilbert is an experienced professional with profound industrial experience and at the time of recording this video (2 July 2021) he was a programme manager at the Netherlands Railways. In this video I ask Wilbert what success has meant to him over the years and how he has approached this subject in his life.</description></item><item><title>Change can be overwhelming, but transformational change leads you to profound growth</title><link>https://yawar5.github.io/website/posts/third-post/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://yawar5.github.io/website/posts/third-post/</guid><description>I have been going through quite a few changes lately and I thought it might be good to document my thoughts at this stage. Once you feel comfortable in a particular place or situation, it is very overwhelming when you have to change, voluntarily or involuntarily. It is also important to note that people are different. While some of us find it relatively easy or fun to experience change, others may find it stressful or even frightening.</description></item><item><title>Strategy document for PS (Prudent Students) charity organisation</title><link>https://yawar5.github.io/website/projects/second-project/</link><pubDate>Sun, 24 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://yawar5.github.io/website/projects/second-project/</guid><description>When, in January 2022, I saw little children going through the rubbish on the streets of Istanbul to collect food scraps, I couldn&amp;rsquo;t help but wonder what role I could play to reduce that child&amp;rsquo;s suffering. Although none of us has a life without problems, it is my humble opinion that seeing people&amp;rsquo;s suffering can help us understand and appreciate what we have even more. Our world is full of such stories and it is very likely that many of us have also struggled in one way or another to get where we are today.</description></item><item><title>Good habits and Technology</title><link>https://yawar5.github.io/website/topics/second-post/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://yawar5.github.io/website/topics/second-post/</guid><description>In December 2021, Miki and I discuss his journey to developing good habits and his passion for new technologies in general and artificial intelligence in particular in this video.
We begin with a general introduction of Miki, which is quickly followed by an in-depth discussion of Miki&amp;rsquo;s journey to self-development and some of the good habits he is pursuing.
We agree that building good habits requires willpower, motivation, consistency and keeping track of your habits.</description></item><item><title>Five principles for a great travelling experience</title><link>https://yawar5.github.io/website/posts/second-post/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://yawar5.github.io/website/posts/second-post/</guid><description>When our plane was about to land at Bucharest International Airport, I was full of all kinds of questions and prejudices about Romania. Having spent only four days in the country and travelled a little, I am filled with appreciation and admiration for this country. It is worth noting that I have seen this pattern repeat itself so many times: we are filled with all kinds of wrong assumptions and prejudices about countries all over the world, but when we actually visit them, we are pleasantly surprised by their hospitality, openness and cultural values.</description></item><item><title>Entrepreneurship</title><link>https://yawar5.github.io/website/topics/first-topic/</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://yawar5.github.io/website/topics/first-topic/</guid><description>In August 2021, after three hours of hiking, Emile and I discuss his journey to entrepreneurship at a beautiful spot on the Italian-Swiss border in the Alps. Where I ask him three questions: 1) What drove him to become an entrepreneur? 2) What challenges does he see for himself in the coming time? 3) What advice or recommendations does he have for others?
I followed up this conversation with him again in May 2021, where after a four-hour hike, Emile and I look back on the past year in which an idea grew into a company called Nebuly.</description></item><item><title>Two lessons I learned from writing eight papers</title><link>https://yawar5.github.io/website/posts/first-post/</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://yawar5.github.io/website/posts/first-post/</guid><description>What have I learned from writing eight papers over the past four years? Although this question can be answered from various angles, such as providing a detailed description of the identified research gaps followed by a critical analysis of the methodologies used and results gathered for each of the eight papers, my focus here is rather simple and straightforward. I would like to share with you some rather more personal and somewhat surprising aspects of the writing of the eight papers.</description></item><item><title>About me</title><link>https://yawar5.github.io/website/about/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://yawar5.github.io/website/about/</guid><description/></item></channel></rss>