<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Topics on Yawar's website</title><link>https://yawar5.github.io/website/topics/</link><description>Recent content in Topics on Yawar's website</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 16 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://yawar5.github.io/website/topics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Good habits and Technology</title><link>https://yawar5.github.io/website/topics/second-post/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://yawar5.github.io/website/topics/second-post/</guid><description>In December 2021, Miki and I discuss his journey to developing good habits and his passion for new technologies in general and artificial intelligence in particular in this video.
We begin with a general introduction of Miki, which is quickly followed by an in-depth discussion of Miki&amp;rsquo;s journey to self-development and some of the good habits he is pursuing.
We agree that building good habits requires willpower, motivation, consistency and keeping track of your habits.</description></item><item><title>Entrepreneurship</title><link>https://yawar5.github.io/website/topics/first-topic/</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://yawar5.github.io/website/topics/first-topic/</guid><description>In August 2021, after three hours of hiking, Emile and I discuss his journey to entrepreneurship at a beautiful spot on the Italian-Swiss border in the Alps. Where I ask him three questions: 1) What drove him to become an entrepreneur? 2) What challenges does he see for himself in the coming time? 3) What advice or recommendations does he have for others?
I followed up this conversation with him again in May 2021, where after a four-hour hike, Emile and I look back on the past year in which an idea grew into a company called Nebuly.</description></item></channel></rss>